

MICHAEL OWENS

Email Marketing Specialist & Front End Engineer 9518805415

O DETAILS O

9518805415 mocoding86@gmail.com

o LINKS o

<u>Portfolio</u>

o SKILLS o

Email Marketing

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Data Analysis

List Management

Graphic Design

Git

GitHub

Wireframing

O HOBBIES O

Gym, snowboarding, hiking, river rafting, beach, new food, new music

PROFILE

I am a passionate email marketing specialist with over 2 years of experience that has dipped into front-end web development. I love learning new technology as there always something new to learn and adjustments being made constantly. I've worked in many ESP platforms and have learned using email template frameworks to code emails from scratch.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Email Marketing Specialist at iMarket Solutions, Costa Mesa

January 2019 — Present

- On-board new clients and meet with 18+ clients monthly to report and strategize campaigns based on previouis data or overall company data
- Set-up new clients in ESP's, design client email templates, create a 3-step automation welcome series for any new subscribers on client websites through our services
- Clean, edit, and segment email marketing lists based on strategies
- Design, create copy, and test email campaigns within ESP for the best deliverability
- Experience creating custom HTML and inline CSS email campaign layouts for mobile responsiveness
- Read and analyze email reporting with custom excel sheets based on results of email campaigns
- QC for other email marketing specialists to ensure the best product is expedited

Notable Company Projects

- Gathered and developed a year-round email strategy based on all 2018 email data (over 550 emails campaigns)
- Led ActiveCampaign BETA testing, developed set-up documentation for ESP transfer from MailChimp to ActiveCampaign and internal company sequences for email marketing department
- Led testing for Stripo Email Templates with templates, documentation, and sequence creation

Email Marketing & Lead Generation Specialist at eLocal Solutions, San Marcos

August 2017 — December 2018

- Experience buying domains with Hostgator and Godaddy and pointing DNS properly, setting up Wordpress CMS, hooking up Google Analytics, Heatmaps such as Crazy Egg, and other various plugins as needed
- Experience with Google Analytics, adding goals, and URL's for campaigns
- Experience with Zoho and Salesforce CRMs internally and use for clients
- Experience hooking up call tracking numbers with the use of Callfire and Call Rail along with SMS text messaging campaigns
- Experience using Agent Legend, an automated voicemail and text messaging campaign
- Proper set-up and implementation of email marketing accounts, from address set-ups and hook-ups with DKIM records and SPF records with the use Act-On, Elastic Email, and SendGrid ESPs with an average of 2 million+ email deliveries per month across multiple clients with an Enterprise Account
- Able to design with the use of Canva, develop and /or create email marketing campaigns for various clients and industries

- Intermediate knowledge of HTML5 & CSS3 and able to build/manipulate emails and/or webpages
- Collaborated with various departments to drive success for client webinar campaigns, nurture automation, and new types of email campaigns and/or functionality
- Split A/B Test for better subject lines and content conversion within emails
- Created and implemented send schedules for email campaigns
- Cleaned, formatted, and segmented email lists based on campaigns
- Able to cross reference between lists with the use of VLOOKUPS in excel
- Analyzed and reported data with the use of Google Analytics in email campaigns and Act-On Software
- Track leads and created custom reporting spreadsheets with the use of excel for clients
- Test and proofread email campaigns and links between different browsers for design issues, mobile friendliness, clarity, grammar, and spelling
- Find, assist, and fix errors on client accounts, websites, and emails
- Up to date with current and emerging trends and methods of digital marketing

EDUCATION

Business Administration AAS, San Joaquin Valley College, Temecula

April 2016 — July 2017

Avg Grade: A+

Activities and Societies: Accountant for Diversity Club

Maintained 4.0 GPA throughout school tenure. Received Passionate Professional Award recognized by students and teachers.

REFERENCES

James Wallace from Tinuiti

jwall3886@gmail.com | (760) 908-2544

Ivan Constantino from San Diego County Office of Education

icaivan11@gmail.com | (760) 289-2981

Nikki Jencen from Certified Coach, Talk Show Host, Marketer

nikkiv26@gmail.com | (262) 613-8267

Cathy Velosky from Hay House, Inc.

veloskey@cox.net

COURSES

Graphic Design Foundations: Layout and Composition, LinkedIn Learning

November 2019 — November 2019

Storytelling for Designers, LinkedIn Learning

September 2019 — September 2019

Hubspot: Email Marketing Certification, Hubspot

July 2019 — July 2019

Email Marketing Optimization, LinkedIn Learning
May 2019 — May 2019

Building an Integrated Online Marketing Plan, LinkedIn Learning
April 2019 — April 2019

Learning to Write Marketing Copy, LinkedIn Learning
April 2019 — April 2019

Email and Newsletter Marketing Foundations, LinkedIn Learning
January 2019 — January 2019

The Complete Javascript Course 2019: Build Real Projects, Udemy
December 2018 — January 2019

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Frontend Engineer at Freelancer, Wildomar

October 2019 — November 2019

I love building real-world projects. Whether its responsive websites, responsive email templates, newsletter sign-ups forms, etc.